<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-01-11T10:49:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Blog</title><entry><title type="html">Thanks, ‘16’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/01/thanks-16.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanks, '16'" /><published>2017-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/01/thanks-16</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2017/01/01/thanks-16.html">&lt;p&gt;2016 was the true realization of Drake’s 2013 hit, Started From The Bottom. At the turn of the previous New Year, I was bound and determined to start fresh. This year I don’t feel the exact same urgency to change my life as dramatically as then, but I count that as a blessing. This year was full of uncomfortable situations that later yielded contentment, negative emotions burned as fuel for inspiration in creation, and lack of control permitting a greater appreciation for when things turn out as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016 I graduated college, moved to a new apartment in Cincinnati, got a job, a cat, and a harp, and travelled to Milwaukee, Chicago, Toronto, LA, Denver, Winter Park, Gold Coast, Melbourne, Kyoto, Osaka, and Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I sought to improve in 2016: saying ‘yes’ more, taking care of my mental health, greater independence, and staying in touch with people who matter to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I kind of bombed in 2016 but forgive myself for because I was concentrating on other things: working out (although I like to think that my new daily 2 mile walk to work and back gets me out of that?), healthy eating, and dwelling on on others’ opinions of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I want to work on in 2017: flossing more, taking care of physical self, not seeking other’s approval, and making stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 was the year I wanted to feel good again. I am so grateful for the fortunate events of this year that made me what I am now—content. Thank you for not just being better, 2016, but for being bigger. I think 2017 will be too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“They say I changed, but what a pity if I stayed the same”&lt;/em&gt;
–Solange&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="new" /><category term="year" /><summary type="html">2016 was the true realization of Drake’s 2013 hit, Started From The Bottom. At the turn of the previous New Year, I was bound and determined to start fresh. This year I don’t feel the exact same urgency to change my life as dramatically as then, but I count that as a blessing. This year was full of uncomfortable situations that later yielded contentment, negative emotions burned as fuel for inspiration in creation, and lack of control permitting a greater appreciation for when things turn out as planned.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wolves by Kanye West Harp Cover</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/music/2016/12/28/wolves.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wolves by Kanye West Harp Cover" /><published>2016-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/music/2016/12/28/wolves</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/music/2016/12/28/wolves.html">&lt;p&gt;video&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been arranging some harp-hop tunes in my spare time and throwing them up on YouTube because I guess that’s the thing to do these days. I’m shooting to get to a more elite recording quality, video, and harp mastery level as life goes on, but I’m enjoying arranging covers like this in the mean time. It’s been a bit longer than a year since I started taking harp lessons and I’ve fallen in love with this expensive, large, and glorious instrument. You can check my humble YouTube channel here for more harp-hop covers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="music" /><category term="harp" /><category term="music" /><category term="cover" /><category term="kanye" /><category term="west" /><category term="hip" /><category term="hop" /><summary type="html">video</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thanks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/11/24/thanks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanks" /><published>2016-11-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/11/24/thanks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2016/11/24/thanks.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am thankful for a family that laughs a lot and enjoys one another’s company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am thankful for friends that bond over mutual weirdness and understand where I come from.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am thankful for a new sweet, funny, soft and fat cat named Gladys.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am thankful for a job that makes me genuinely pumped to wake up each day and coworkers that rule.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am thankful for my mental and physical health.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am thankful for my cozy apartment and the city that holds it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am thankful for the ways that music and art enrich my life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am thankful for everything that gives life beauty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="thoughts" /><category term="thoughts" /><category term="thanksgiving" /><summary type="html">I am thankful for a family that laughs a lot and enjoys one another’s company.
  I am thankful for friends that bond over mutual weirdness and understand where I come from.
  I am thankful for a new sweet, funny, soft and fat cat named Gladys.
  I am thankful for a job that makes me genuinely pumped to wake up each day and coworkers that rule.
  I am thankful for my mental and physical health.
  I am thankful for my cozy apartment and the city that holds it.
  I am thankful for the ways that music and art enrich my life.
  I am thankful for everything that gives life beauty.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cincinnati Saturdays</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/photography/thoughts/2016/11/05/cincinnati-saturdays.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cincinnati Saturdays" /><published>2016-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/photography/thoughts/2016/11/05/cincinnati-saturdays</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/photography/thoughts/2016/11/05/cincinnati-saturdays.html">&lt;p&gt;Northside_15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yo blog, I ain’t seen you in a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot has changed in two months. Last time I was here, I was in the process of writing up a post about the adventures of being unemployed. I’m glad I never had to finish that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get into what I really came here for, I’ll supply a brief update. On September 6, I started my first real full-time job as a UX Designer at Gaslight, a software development consultancy in Cincinnati, Ohio. Long story short: I love it, I’m extremely grateful for how everything turned out, and I couldn’t have found a better fit. After a long, discouraging bout with the job search process, I ended up with my first choice with unbelievable relief. You can read more about my employed adventures in my Gaslight blog post here. A month after I started, I moved to Cincinnati from Middletown, settling in the hood of Mount Adams. I can walk downtown to work, to Eden Park, and to the Art Museum from my place, and I’m developing solid calf and gluteal muscles from all of the incline hiking that living in this charming mountain neighborhood requires. Everything has fallen into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m tickled to say that adjusting to a full time work routine hasn’t been as rocky of a transition as I assumed. It helps that I was very, very ready to start working towards the end of my obligation-free summer. The weirdest part now is figuring out what my evenings and weekends aside from work look like. What am I supposed to do by myself in this new apartment when I’m not going to Home Depot or Target or working up a stress sweat from hanging a shelf on my hard-to-drill-through walls? I don’t have my course schedule to direct me on how to incorporate my interests into my life and personal work. No more orchestra concerts, quartet practices, photo critiques, or late nights in the darkroom. My extra-curricular passions operate on my own terms now. This is good and bad, I’m finding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do I do? I love routine, and it helps occupy my mind. But I also need to lean against it, and find new ways to live in the day-to-day outside my comfort zone. It’s funny how much I take for granted now that I live here. Things that I used to take day trips to see, I now ignore because they’re at an arm’s reach. I have to force myself to step outside my front stairs and see my own city as a tourist like I used to. So that my mind will be stimulated, my sense of wonder enriched, and my youth preserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically, I need to keep walking. I came up with this idea: every Saturday (winter months, permitting), I will explore a new neighborhood in Cincinnati. Just walking, with my camera. Emphasis on the camera, because lately I’ve been developing an irrational fear of taking photos. That’s weird, you might say, because I identify as a photographer. I love it, but here’s a little secret: it scares me. This little anxiety makes me sad and makes me miss out on photo opportunities a more bold me might take. However, once I get in the groove of making photographs, I forget about it. The hard part is getting myself to that place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came up with this idea today while exploring one of my new favorite spots: Northside. It’s a shame I didn’t think of this idea last weekend when I took a 7 mile trek to Findlay Market and clear to Kentucky and back. My glutes felt that. Today I wandered around in observation, stopping to eat one of the best chocolate chip cookies I’ve ever had at Sidewinder Coffee and finding the planner of my dreams at Shake It Records (an unlikely place to find a planner, which added to the enchantment). The neighborhood reminded me of a more diverse Yellowsprings and was a very pleasant place to walk and soak up the last of the Daylight Savings Time sun. I liked the unexpectedness of what you might see on the street. Northside isn’t as polished as other Cincinnati neighborhoods, but much more colorful and eclectic, making for many photos. After that I headed back to my own neighborhood for an afternoon walk to the Cincinnati Art Museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NorthsideNorthside_10Northside_3Northside_13Northside_1Northside_14Northside_7Northside_8Northside_9Northside_5Northside_4Northside_6Northside_2I can’t wait to keep walking. Before I walk, I always worry that the residents of the place will be able to point me out as an outsider. Or that they’ll look at me funny for seeing the potential in things that don’t seem worthy of photographing. I worry that my effort to get to this place will be for naught and I will just end up tired. But today was a very good day. I discovered treasures. I was present. And I was very glad I walked.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="photography" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html">Northside_15</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Take Your Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/doodles/thoughts/2016/08/22/take-your-time.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Take Your Time" /><published>2016-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/doodles/thoughts/2016/08/22/take-your-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/doodles/thoughts/2016/08/22/take-your-time.html">&lt;p&gt;takeyourtime&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a month and 10 days that I’ve been back home from mega-trip 2016. It’s strange to keep defining my life by the time since a trip, but that is the last logical landmark I’ve experienced, so alas. In this month and 10 days, I’ve been trying to get back into the groove of life and what that means for me in such a transitional season. When you’re living out of a suitcase, you quickly realize the aspects of life that you miss and the endeavors you need to spend your time pursuing. When I got back in my beloved bedroom full of all my wonderful musical instruments, books, craft supplies, cameras, classical composer busts, and mini cat figurines I was back in hobby heaven. All that time spent in awesome locations with limited resources left me oh so ready to dive head first into all of my passions once again. I found myself more ready than ever to learn, evolve, and create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of all the things that have happened in my hobby-sphere in the past month and 10 days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day after I got back from Colorado, I drove to Bloomington, Indiana to purchase a harp.
I fell in love with this harp, so I started a YouTube channel for harp covers. So far my only post is a Rihanna song, but I hope to add more minor-keyed hip-hop songs very soon. Destiny child is up next.
I’ve done a lot of work amping up this website, adding more content, details, and photos in the galleries. I’ve also been learning some new web design techniques. You probably can’t tell much difference, but I recently completely gutted my CSS. I cleansed hundreds of lines of unused code and started using the pre-processor, Sass, to keep my code more organized.
I’ve submitted photography work to multiple galleries. I’m currently preparing for Summerfair Streetfair in Cincinnati this September, where I’ll have a booth with some prints.
I’ve been freelancing often, doing logo and web design, photography, and more recently, crafts.
I realized one of my passions is embroidering hip-hop lyrics onto fabric. I opened an Etsy shop and started selling some pieces at a super cool store in Middletown called Society.
I’ve been getting more serious about making my own music, which is always something I’ve dabbled in. I’ve just been playing around with Ableton Live again so we’ll see where it goes.
Upon realizing I cleansed out my accounts while traveling, I started pursuing as many strategies of making money online as I could find. This includes but is not limited to Ebay, Etsy, Upwork, 99Designs, UserTesting.com, focus groups, online surveys, Wonder, and multiple iPhone apps. I then realized that there is no good way to make money online.
I’ve learned the wonder that traveling can do for your inspiration, productivity, self-improvement, and general interest in life. I’ve been turbo-charged, running full force in every direction that peaks my interest this month and 10 days. But I’ve learned the hard way that sometimes I need to slow it down. When I want something very badly, I lose a handle on my patience. I go 0 to 100 real quick. In the heat of the moment I am blind to the fact that I can not learn a violin concerto or new programming language or &lt;em&gt;insert difficult but intriguing skill here&lt;/em&gt; in a day. It’s just not possible and it’s not a good way to learn. Too often I set goals too high and beat myself up when I fall short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;todo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a quality about me that I simultaneously am grateful for and fear above all else. It’s the desire to be good. My self esteem depends too heavily on my successes and I am devastated by my failure. I need to learn how to get the small things done before tackling the big things, all at once. Practice my scales. Have patience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need a masters in psychology to understand the minefield of my brain. I need to set real goals. I set goals alright, but I break them and make them too high and get frustrated if I can’t become a master in a day. But people say it takes 10,000 hours to become a master. If you break that down into an hour of practice a day, that makes 27 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of creative people have this war with themselves. It hinders productivity, confidence, and self esteem. It doesn’t have to be this way. If I can learn to learn correctly and have constructive, healthy conversations with myself while I’m practicing and growing, it would make a world’s difference. Mental strength can cure a multitude of ills. Learning how to do this is the foundation of success and mental stability in creative fields. I write this with the hope that I will follow my own advice. So for goodness sake, take your time, sister. Enjoy the learning process. Know that it could take 27+ years for you to become a master. And that you can’t get anywhere with talent alone because you also need hard work. Set reachable goals for yourself and recognize your feats no matter how small. If you keep practicing, putting that time in day by day and never giving up, you’ll get somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="doodles" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html">takeyourtime</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflection on Traveling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/thoughts/2016/07/16/traveling-a-reflection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection on Traveling" /><published>2016-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/thoughts/2016/07/16/traveling-a-reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/thoughts/2016/07/16/traveling-a-reflection.html">&lt;p&gt;Colorado_2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sitting on a 12 hour and 5 minute flight across the Pacific from Brisbane to LA. Two hours before landing, a flight attendant announces over the intercom, “If we have any medical doctors on board please make yourself known to the flight attendant.” I look to the aisle ahead to my right. A woman who looks a few years older than me is lying on the floor, surrounded by two flight attendants and her friend. With no doctors available, they move the woman to a curtained chamber and place an oxygen mask on her face. Thirty minutes before landing, the woman is moved 3 rows ahead of me into a seat and I see a wide stroke of blood on her back. Throughout the flight, another person a few rows ahead vomits into the “Feeling sick?” curtsey paper bag 3 times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, my anxiety is taking a physical form that no amount of deep breathing can stop. I complain of having heartburn and numbness in my left arm that is not routine for my body. I honestly believe that I might have a heart attack on this plane, no matter how unreasonable that seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a week since I arrived home after spending 6 weeks traveling to LA, Melbourne, Tokyo, Kyoto, Osaka, Brisbane, Denver, and Winter Park, Colorado. I had a good portion of time to ponder the meaning of travel and the human motivation to do so. I quickly realized that living out of a suitcase for a month and a half starts to wear on a person. The sleeping in unfamiliar beds, the scattering of belongings, the lack of ownership of dwelling places, the walking farther than your arches can support, the 24-hour flights, are all key components of traveling that are often overlooked with the eagerness of the planning period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ColoradoCan we just talk about how much traveling can suck sometimes? I know it’s not all bad, of course, and I do not mean to complain about the great privilege I’ve had to see some of the world. But I don’t think people talk about the bad parts of traveling very much. I like to think that there’s a distinction to be made between “traveling” and “vacation.” There’s nothing more glamorized among 20-something hipsters than traveling and adventure. There is no better way to show people from high school that you’re going far in life than by posting pictures of yourself in foreign countries on Instagram. The word adventure is tossed around like a sack of potatoes and I’ll be honest, the ball’s in my court too. But I think we can all be honest for a moment and say that a lot of what we do isn’t really adventure at all. Taking a plane ride? Not really an adventure. Taking a bus tour? Nah. Walking to a wooded area and not doing anything remotely risky at all? Nope. But it’s fun to use the word and try to get away with it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s something a lot of people won’t tell you: traveling alone to new places for 6 weeks is really hard. In the beginning, I had the mindset that my experience should be treated more like a vacation and that I should try to enjoy myself and be in good spirits the whole time. That’s my OCD kicking in, trying to discipline myself into happiness (which is never effective). But to grow, you need to do hard things. You need to be uncomfortable and unhappy sometimes to get from point A to point B. We’re creatures that thrive off of sensing differences. It’s why the rich get used to living in luxury and why we all seek different haircuts and clothes and home decor. It’s a good reason that we crave to leave where we live and get out into a different part of the world every once and awhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My one question to more seasoned travelers is if they ever reach a point where they feel like they can no longer embrace the open road. I thought I hit a wall near the end of my trip where I was no longer open and ready to experience new things. I just wanted to be home so I could get back to work on all the projects I had left. If humans need change, what happens when change is the norm? I mean, can people travel constantly through their life and remain in awe and inspired by the world around? The romanticizing of travel makes it appear like it’s the absolute highest tier of human experience and can never be grown tired of. But my hunch is that there comes a point where you need to be “home” too. I think a good balance keeps the mind open and ready for the lessons to be learned both in new experiences and old. I could just be a high strung homebody, but if anyone out there has traveled for years at a time, I would be interested to hear the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I sat on that 12 hour and 5 minute plane ride, I wondered if a 46-day anxiety attack was really worth the travel experience. I didn’t anticipate to have such severe side effects of anxiety, but I suppose my body and unreasonable unconscious mind had other plans. Not a day passed where I didn’t consciously fear death abundantly with every mode of transportation taken or street corner turned. Fireworks in the night that to me sounded like live gun shots. Pains in strange areas that made me believe I would soon mysteriously perish from an undisclosed disease. Walks from sets of legs too close behind that made me feel on the verge of being kidnapped or worse. It was unreasonable, but it was real, and it builded and builded. I wondered if perhaps I wasn’t good enough to travel alone extensively. There’s something to be said for conquering your fears. But there’s a difference between fear and it’s cousin, anxiety. So, what happens when you try to actively conquer your anxieties? Why does it feel like the more I put myself in situations that intersect with anxiety triggers, the more my physical symptoms of the disorder increase and increase?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get this straight-there’s nothing brave about me. I’m a hidden wimp. All you have to do to travel alone is be someone that both enjoys your own company and who won’t wait up for anyone. When people let me down and showed they weren’t worthy of my trust I turned around and told myself to do something on my own, to be my own savior. I’m just someone who is over-anxious but fakes it until I can finally feel like a reasonable being. I planned this trip when I was in a bad place mentally, and it wouldn’t have happened if I hadn’t endured such. I planned it to give me hope, to get my mind off things, to have something worthwhile in my future when it all seemed dark. And frankly, I was just crazy enough at the time to do it. I’m thankful for not being entirely sane. I’m thankful for the grave times that made me feel so worthless and defeated that it gave me no choice but to book flights for one to foreign countries. If I had been a happy person at the time, none of it would have happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colorado_1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why do we travel? To experience other cultures, to “find ourselves”, to relax, to practice living in the moment, to enjoy life, to make memories, to get out of the house? There’s plenty of good reasons, but when the going gets tough, it’s easy to ask yourself what’s really in it for you. It’s not always the most enjoyable thing in the moment if I’m honest with myself, but there are many great things that came out of it. For example, I no longer feel fear when eating alone. I now feel more confident, more able to articulate my feelings and opinions without fear. Traveling taught me that there are many types of people and cultures and social norms. What’s normal for one group can be foreign for the other. And when you live long enough deep inside one culture, it’s hard to see out into the thousands of others. You realize it’s okay to feel weird or to feel like you don’t fit in because where you live represents a small portion of society and there are billions of others out there with different backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For my part, I travel not to go anywhere, but to travel for travel’s sake. The great affair is to move; to feel the needs and hitches of our life more nearly; to come down off this feather-bed of civilization, and find the glove granite underfoot and strewn with cutting flints.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Robert Louis Stevenson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traveling alone was lonely at times. It wasn’t the funnest company to have socially on such a trip, but from a soul searching perspective it was optimal. There’s something that can’t be replaced when you’re traveling outside of your own company. People are great, but you don’t get the exact same experience. When you’re alone, each decision is yours and each path you take impacts you and only you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we practice traveling not only to see other pockets of the world, but to practice awe, observation, and living in the moment. Getting out gives us new reasons to live. The best thoughts and ideas come about when walking or going somewhere and I thrive off the burst of creativity I get. “Methinks that the moment my legs begin to move, my thoughts begin to flow,” said Henry David Thoreau. We need difference, we need change, and we need new directions every once and awhile. We need time to engage in our surroundings and senses, and we need time to disengage. We need people and we need alone time. We need home and we need new roads to travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colorado_43&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one of the last days of my trip, I hiked one of Colorado’s 14er mountains, Gray’s Peak. It was absolutely terrible most of the time. The beauty of hiking is once you get to the peak, the trauma of the ascent is erased completely. I’m convinced this is the only way that people hike. Does anyone even truly like hiking? I mean can you truly love anything? Because I don’t know if anyone else has noticed, but everything in life is really hard. As Rihanna states, “work, work, work, work, work.” I couldn’t have said it better myself. As usual, it’s my mind that most often gets in my way at tough times such as mountain climbing. I start to think that I can’t do anything and I start to mentally give up on all of my life dreams one by one, but then finally I arrive at my destination and my mind makes a 180 turn for the better. When you doubt if you can do anything of difficulty or challenge, remember that it’s in your blood to fight, to do hard things. It’s the instinct that will eventually take over you when you least expect it. It’s why you’re still alive. It’s why humans have survived through all the years. You may feel weak now, but a wave will come that will give you energy and inspiration to do something really hard and you’ll be grateful for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You must habit yourself to the dazzle of the light and of every moment of your life”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Walt Whitman&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="travel" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html">Colorado_2</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sarah Portraits</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/photography/2016/07/14/sarah-portraits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sarah Portraits" /><published>2016-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/photography/2016/07/14/sarah-portraits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/photography/2016/07/14/sarah-portraits.html">&lt;p&gt;Sarah_144
Every once and awhile, I like to post portraits that I’m really proud of. It’s summer now and the warm evening light is a gorgeous daily event; one that I’ve missed while not being able to embrace it as much while traveling. The other day I got to photograph my friend Sarah, and it was one of those perfect July nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I feel like I’m not really cut out to be a portrait photographer. I’m not super outgoing, not good at coming up with the right words to say, not good at making babies smile, I embarrass myself under pressure, and the list goes on. But I forget that I really love taking portraits. Once I’m in the moment, my immense anxiety goes away and I can just make photographs and if I’m lucky, make art. Portrait and art photography are not entire different entities, as I sometimes blindly believe. They influence each other, as any part of you influences all that you do. Even when I’m working on personal work I find that I’m composing my frames like I would a portrait, but instead of working with flesh I’m trying to breathe life into objects. That is where I find that portrait and non-portrait photography intersect. And although I avoided portrait photography for a long time, whether due to anxiety, lack of subjects, introversion, mild anti-socialism, or laziness, I’ve found that it’s a very expressive genre that I love working in and can do. It’s an interesting dynamic, watching my portrait work interact with my personal work and vise versa. In photography, in talents, and in life, I think it’s important to keep every part of you active and alive, never cutting off anything that you’re passionate about. I think the intersections of these contrasting things speak to each other and grow deeper roots in all directions, and that can be inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ramblings aside, here’s some of my favorite photos from Sarah’s portrait session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_40&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_151&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_31&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_9&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_147&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_72&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_157&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_88&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_207&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_161
 Sarah_181&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_67&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_186&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_166
SarahBW_195
SarahBW_174&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_156
SarahBW_199&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_162&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_133
SarahBW_187
Sarah_131&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_105&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_53&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah_98&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SarahBW_178&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="photography" /><category term="photography" /><category term="portraits" /><summary type="html">Sarah_144
Every once and awhile, I like to post portraits that I’m really proud of. It’s summer now and the warm evening light is a gorgeous daily event; one that I’ve missed while not being able to embrace it as much while traveling. The other day I got to photograph my friend Sarah, and it was one of those perfect July nights.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Japan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/photography/travel/2016/07/11/japan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Japan" /><published>2016-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/photography/travel/2016/07/11/japan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/photography/travel/2016/07/11/japan.html">&lt;p&gt;Kyoto_70&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have little to say about Japan. I’m really at a loss for words. Not because there’s nothing to talk about, but because there is just so much. It’s a place with so much beauty, culture, and history that I don’t feel comfortable speaking on it’s behalf. I want everyone to get to go to Japan. There’s a quiet in the way Japan presents itself that is uniquely mesmerizing. Not only is Japan the most photogenic place I have ever been, but it seems photography is more welcome there. Maybe it was the language barrier, but I no longer felt as shy reaching my camera out. I felt my creative ideas running a little dry before this trip, but it seemed like Japan was a place that shared a voice similar to the one I wanted to express. It was like a visually perfect dream that was actually real. So if it’s alright with you, I think I’ll just let the pictures talk for the most part this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my 9 days in Japan, I started and ended my trip in Tokyo, taking the Shinkansen to Kyoto and Osaka for a few days in between. In Kyoto, I encountered some of the country’s most precious landmarks. I mean that city had shrines on shrines and temples on temples. So many shrines and temples. It was beautiful, but with beauty comes tourists, and with tourists comes stress and slightly bad moods on my part. I made the most of it and tried to find the places that were more remote and peaceful, which Kyoto has plenty of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KyotoBW_12KyotoBW_7Kyoto_220KyotoBW_5Kyoto_248Kyoto_208KyotoBW_1Kyoto_136KyotoBW_28Kyoto_39&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Kyoto, I took a one-night side trip to Osaka to get a glimpse of another Japanese city. I mostly wandered with no destination in mind. I stumbled into a 6-floor arcade that was the most magical place I had ever seen. I knew Japan loved video games, but it was more grand that I could’ve imagined. Japan has a way of making you feel like you’ve entered another world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osaka_26Osaka_27 Osaka_24 Osaka_17 Osaka_15 Osaka_13Osaka_5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Kyoto and Osaka, it was back to the main event, Tokyo. Tokyo is probably the best city in the world, but I haven’t seen all of them so I’m not allowed to say that. I’ve never been somewhere so urban and vast, yet so quiet and peaceful at the same time. The people are nice, it’s clean, and it’s extremely safe. The biggest city in the world is bursting with life in every corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TokyoBW_55Tokyo_317 TokyoBW_30Tokyo_166 Tokyo_323TokyoBW_12 Tokyo_320Tokyo_286 Tokyo_297Tokyo_285 Tokyo_281TokyoBW_65 Tokyo_258 Tokyo_191Tokyo_194 Tokyo_229 TokyoBW_48 Tokyo_230 Tokyo_232 Tokyo_182Tokyo_143 Tokyo_135 Tokyo_133TokyoBW_71 Tokyo_129TokyoBW_43 Tokyo_26 Tokyo_42 Tokyo_51Tokyo_70 Tokyo_25 Tokyo_23TokyoBW_67Tokyo_61&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’ll probably be unfortunate in the future, finding out that one of the first countries I ever visited can’t be topped. I can’t wait to go back someday, but in the meantime I think Japan will be a place that I find myself dreaming about often.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="photography" /><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Kyoto_70</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Australia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/photography/travel/2016/07/03/australia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Australia" /><published>2016-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/photography/travel/2016/07/03/australia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/photography/travel/2016/07/03/australia.html">&lt;p&gt;GoldCoast_28
Australia, the land down under. The country of numerous dangerous and venomous creatures, kangaroos and koalas, beaches, the Outback, and accents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending a VERY long time in planes and airports, I arrived in Melbourne, Victoria. The first day was full of great adventure and life-changing experiences (I fell asleep at 4pm). My first day in Australia taught me one thing and it is that jet lag is very real. Fourteen hours later, I woke up feeling guilty so I pushed myself out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I soon discovered that Melbourne is the kind of city that if it weren’t a 24-hour plane journey from home, I would seriously consider living in. It’s extremely walkable, feels reasonably safe (compared to US cities), has plenty of art and culture, and is just generally pretty fun. Unique to Melbourne (unless they have them in other cities I haven’t visited), are the laneways that weave between the main streets. They’re used as hubs for street art, shops, and the restaurants that all the cool Australians seem to eat at (but I didn’t feel cool enough to eat alone at because I have an inferiority complex, so I stuck to less cool dining options).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent my time in Melbourne walking myself to exhaustion, but all for a good cause. Half of the time I wandered around, with no real destination in mind. I find that often the best treasures are found when you aren’t looking for them. Some of the highlights I saw of the city were the Queen Victoria Market, Royal Botanic Gardens, Australian Centre for the Moving Image, the Old Melbourne Goal, and the State Library of Victoria. But really, my favorite places were the ones that I stumbled upon randomly; the ones with no real names. Laneways, paths along the river, compositions in space, medians where street performers sang, posted up signs on building walls, slants of light along tree lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It is not down in any map; true places never are.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Herman Melville&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melbourne_111Melbourne_84Melbourne_11&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Florida_12 copy copyEmpty_7
Melbourne_74&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I left Melbourne, I headed for JAPAN. That was a huge journey in and of itself, so I’ll save that for my next post and skip that part for now. Fast forward 10 days, and I was back in Australia, but this time in Gold Coast, Queensland. I stayed with my Australian family, who taught me all about their country on their yearly visits to the States growing up. I thought I was up to date on the Aussie lingo, but really nothing can prepare you for the vast amount of unique words and phrases that Australians have for things. My personal favorite: “Good on ya,” among others. I also wasn’t prepared for the weather, as I ignored all warnings to bring a good jacket for Australia’s “winter.” I laughed at those wearing winter coats in 60 degree weather, but deep inside I must admit that coatless Ohioan me was chilly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was back in Australia, I wasn’t overly adventurous at first. Walking in Japan for a week and a half on top of the traveling I had done leading up to it left me extremely lethargic. I had spent one layover day before departing for Japan in Surfer’s Paradise, which is exactly what it sounds like. The sun was out and I walked along the beach, in awe of the waves and spotless shore. Australia’s coastline is known for it’s beauty and surf, and it definitely wasn’t a letdown. My favorite beach spot was Byron Bay, which is a neat little town right on the beach. There we hiked out to a lookout and lighthouse, spotting schools of dolphins and even whales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GoldCoast_2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GoldCoastBW_27GoldCoast_20&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting my depleted energy at least half back, I made it out to a rainforest in Springbrook. While it wasn’t the constant downpour that I imagined, it held some of the most beautiful nature sights I saw in Australia. While the country is too big to easily see icons like the Great Barrier Reef and the Outback all in one trip, I was satisfied enough to see some of the majestic parks and forests in the Gold Coast area. One of my main missions for Australia was to see a wild kangaroo and on the last day, after seeing dozens of domesticated ones at the Currumbin Wildlife Sanctuary, I finally saw some through the car window on the way home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GoldCoast_7GoldCoastBW_8GoldCoast_16GoldCoastBW_5GoldCoast_19Sky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the last night in Australia, I looked up into the clear night sky. The southern constellations were unfamiliar, like a new realm of space to discover. It was strange, knowing I’d be heading back to America, not knowing when I would again be in a foreign land such as this. Traveling, something that is usually a temporary novelty, was starting to feel like the norm. I knew things would feel different back in my home country. Things would be more routine, although with plenty to discover yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a weird feeling being somewhere, knowing you might never be back in that same place again. And If you happen to arrive again, things would not be the same. You would be different and your combinations of emotions and thoughts and circumstances would be different. It’s so hard to latch on to the meaning of passing moments. It seems like I can never get the full picture of a situation, a moment, or a place until I’ve grown past it. So much talk is about living in the moment, but what do I have to do, to live a speck in time to my fullest capacity? Do I close my eyes? Or yell into the air that I’m alive? I don’t know if any of us really know how to feel moments fully. Maybe the most we can do is live in awe as best we can, leaving the rest for the reflection of our memories.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="photography" /><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">GoldCoast_28
Australia, the land down under. The country of numerous dangerous and venomous creatures, kangaroos and koalas, beaches, the Outback, and accents.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Outline of the Things I’ve Been Thinking About While Abroad</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/travel/2016/06/26/an-outline.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Outline of the Things I've Been Thinking About While Abroad" /><published>2016-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/travel/2016/06/26/an-outline</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/travel/2016/06/26/an-outline.html">&lt;p&gt;1.jpg
2.jpg
3.jpg
3.5.jpg
4.jpg&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="thoughts" /><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">1.jpg
2.jpg
3.jpg
3.5.jpg
4.jpg</summary></entry></feed>
